Qtips UP219
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Qtips
1996 -- 2004
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lesbian Gay Bisexual Transgender Center
UP219
0.5 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the Queer Community Newsletter of Tufts University. Created by The Lesbian Gay Bisexual Transgender Center.
Biographical / Historical
In 1972 the Tufts Gay Community (TGC) organization was formed to provide a space for gay and bisexual people to meet and support one another and to educate the university community about gay related issues. Although the term "lesbian" was not included in the group name until 1981, the TGC's goal was to shed light on the issues facing the gay and lesbian community on campus. In 1980 the TGC established the first "drop-in center" on campus in Curtis Hall. By October 1987, the drop-in center was moved to Hayes House and In September of 1988, Donna Penn was hired as the first coordinator to increase programming and support services.
In 1992, with support from students, faculty and staff, Dean B. Knable established the first Lesbian Gay and Bisexual (LGB) Resource Center at Tufts in Lewis Hall and Heather Wishik replaced Donna Penn as administrator. After the holding of the first Pride on the Hill event in November 1992, the Center underwent a number of staff changes in the mid-1990s. This included the hiring of the first full-time director, Judith Brown in 1997.
In September 1998, the Tufts Rainbow House was established to provide safe housing for LGBT people on campus in light of the high number of bias incidents that occurred in residence halls. In January 2003 Dona Yarbrough was hired as the LGBT Center Director and began to push for a housing policy that would accommodate transgender students at Tufts. In the fall of 2004, Yarbrough's Transgender Housing Policy was adopted by Residential Life and the Center also began organizing its Queer Peer mentoring program. Upon the suggestion of Yarbrough, the administration accepted a revision to Tufts University non-discrimination policy by adding gender identity and expression in the fall of 2005. From 1997 until the present, the LGBT Center has organized annual and statewide Safe Colleges Conferences, originally called "Sound Mind, Sound Body, Sound Off." The conferences include a keynote speaker and workshops created by staff and organizations, both from campus and off-campus.
Under the umbrella of the Dean of Students, the LGBT Center is part of the Group of Six, which includes: Women's Center, Africana Center, Latino Center, Asian American Center, and the International Center.
- Qtips, 1996 -- 2004; UP219.001; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the Queer Community Newsletter of Tufts University. Created by The Lesbian Gay Bisexual Transgender Center.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Qtips, 1996 November; UP219.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Volume, issue
    1, 1
  - Qtips, 1997 February; UP219.001.001.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.75 Megabytes (Box 1)
    1, 2
  - Qtips, 1997 March; UP219.001.001.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.58 Megabytes (Box 1)
    1, 3
  - Qtips, 1997 April; UP219.001.001.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.39 Megabytes (Box 1)
    1, 4
  - Qtips, 1998 April; UP219.001.001.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 3.32 Megabytes (Box 1)
    2, 3
  - Qtips, 1998 October; UP219.001.001.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.55 Megabytes (Box 1)
    3, 1
  - Qtips, 1999 January 25; UP219.001.001.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.61 Megabytes (Box 1)
    3, 2
  - Qtips, 1999 April 01; UP219.001.001.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.33 Megabytes (Box 1)
    3, 3
  - Qtips, 2001 September; UP219.001.001.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.56 Megabytes (Box 1)
    6, 1
  - QTips, 2002 September; UP219.001.001.00010; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.35 Megabytes (Box 1)
    7, 1
  - QTips, 2003 March; UP219.001.001.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.46 Megabytes (Box 1)
    8, 2
  - QTips, 2003 September; UP219.001.001.00012; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.2 Megabytes (Box 1)
    9, 1
  - QTips, 2003 October; UP219.001.001.00013; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.53 Megabytes (Box 1)
    9, 2
  - QTips, 2003 November; UP219.001.001.00014; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.28 Megabytes (Box 1)
    9, 3
  - QTips, 2004 March; UP219.001.001.00015; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.23 Megabytes (Box 1)
    9, 4
  - QTips, 2004 September; UP219.001.001.00016; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.22 Megabytes (Box 1)
    10, 1